该死
Damn it!
不在 请留言
Not here. Leave a message.
Vince 是我
Vince, it's me.
我要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
给我回电话
Call me when you get this.
不是吧
Oh, come on.
是谁
Hello?
有人么
Somebody there?
Loki
Loki.
你把我吓个半死
You scared me half to death.
快进屋去
Go on, get inside.
Loki 我不是跟你说了么...
Loki, I thought I told you to...
本字幕仅作学习交流之用 禁止用于任何商业用途 否则后果自负
==GA字幕组==
翻译：小末 小白 寂静流年 清欢仰慕者 汤汤忙忙忙 师太
校对：寂静流年 清欢仰慕者 师太
总校：毯子  时间轴：笑傲绿茶
英文字幕：elderman
好了 我的 开我的
Okay, open mine. Open mine.
噢
Oh.
喔
宝宝的第一件白大褂
Baby's first lab coat.
-耶 -噢
- Yay. - Oh.
这个是...
Uh, is it made of, um...?
百分百纯棉 没错
100% cotton, yes.
那你有没有...
And did you....?
我剪掉了所有纽扣 放心
And I removed all the buttons, yes.
避免窒息危险
Choking hazard averted.
-A+ Abby -噢不
- A-plus, Abby. - Oh, no!
你们没等我就开始了 抱歉我来晚了
You started without me. Sorry I'm late.
Tony 我们以为你忘了
Tony, we thought you forgot.
恰恰相反 小麦兄
Au contraire, McFrère.
我可不会错过这个
I wouldn't have missed this.
已经盼了好久了
Been looking forward to it for weeks.
精灵妈妈 精灵爸爸
Mama Gremlin, Papa Gremlin,
Tony之前给Jimmy起的外号叫精灵
这是送给你们俩的礼物
this basket's for you.
谢谢你呀 Tony
Thank you, Tony.
我们看看 呃...
Let's see. Uh...
工业级别的耳塞
Uh, industrial-grade earplugs?
没错 这个可有用啦
Yes, those are gonna come in handy.
宝宝很吵的
Babies are loud.
一瓶波尔多酒
Bottle of Bordeaux.
还有
And, um...
百元大钞
hundred dollars in cash.
Tony 这礼物太差劲了
Tony, those are terrible gifts.
永远不要怀疑DiNozzo家的父母之道
Never knock the DiNozzo parenting method.
我是说
I mean,
看我出落得多么风流倜傥
look how I turned out.
咳
Um,
亲爱的
babe? Mm?
你能去给我倒点水吗
Will you please go get me some water?
没问题 不过其实...
Sure, but, you know, actually, the, uh...
这里的水PH值非常高 不过不要慌
the pH levels up here are really high, so don't panic.
我在解剖室里存了些紧急备用的
I have an emergency stash down in Autopsy.
好
Okay.
听好了各位 我需要帮助
Listen up, guys, I need your help.
怎么了
What's wrong?
是Jimmy 他快把我弄疯了
It's Jimmy. He's driving me crazy.
他什么也不让我吃不让我喝
He-he won't let me eat or drink anything
除非他检验过那东西对宝宝来说够安全
until he checks to make sure it's safe for the baby.
噢 他只是小心谨慎些
Oh, I mean, he's just being cautious.
我只想静一静
All I want is peace and quiet.
还想吃芝士汉堡
And a cheeseburger.
你们一定得帮我
You guys have to help me.
编造出个案子啥的
I mean, make up a case or something.
呃 这招可能行不通
Yeah, it doesn't really work that way.
带好装备 瀑布教堂市有海军上尉身亡
Grab your gear. Dead navy lieutenant in Falls Church.
噢 感谢上帝
Oh, thank God.
我是说 抱歉 这太糟糕了
I mean... Sorry. That-That's awful.
有什么发现 Duck
What do you got, Duck?
胸前有枪伤
Uh, gunshot wounds to the chest.
看上去是三处
Three by the look of it.
Palmer先生怎么还没来
What on earth is holding Mr. Palmer?
-还有其它发现么 -有
- You got anything else? - Yeah.
看起来死者生前跟别人打了一架
It appears our victim engaged in a bout of fisticuffs.
如果是跟凶手的打斗
If it was with his killer,
我们或许可以提取到DNA
we may be able to pull DNA.
死亡时间
Time of death, Duck?
差不多昨天午夜
Uh, around midnight last night.
老大 我们发现了一个脚印
Boss, we got a boot print.
杀手并没有
Shooter didn't police
清理现场
his brass.
三个点22口径的弹壳
Three .22 casings.
看来不像是职业杀手
Hmm. Not exactly dealing with a pro.
不过他也够聪明
Well, he was smart enough
知道用消音器
to use a silencer.
没有人向警方报告听到枪声
Police had reports of no gunfire.
-死者身份 -海军上尉
- Victim? - Navy Lieutenant
Eric Kutzler 28岁
Eric Kutzler, 28.
海蜂把他分配到海军后勤部
Seabee assigned him to Naval Support Unit
海蜂指Navy Construction Battalion（海军建设兵团）Seabee是其缩写CB的谐音
为国务院工作
for the State Department.
-目击者 -呃
- Witnesses? - Well,
有一条邻居家的狗
there was the neighbor's dog
名字叫做"Lockey"
whose name is "Lockey."
是"loki"
It's "Loki."
Loki 就是那个阿斯加德王子
Loki, as in the prince of Asgard?
恶作剧之神
The god of mischief?
出自雷神漫画 Tony
From the Thor comics, Tony.
雷神 这里都被死宅们占领了
Thor. The nerds are taking over.
就剩你跟我了 老大
It's just you and me now, boss.
我去检查一下...
I'm-I'm gonna go check the...
检查一下房间
gonna check the house.
我去询问邻居
I'll question the neighbors.
我去别处拍照
I'm gonna go take photos someplace else.
看起来是打碎的玻璃杯
Looks like a broken drinking glass.
可能是打斗中摔碎的
Could be from a struggle.
但是 其它东西都井井有条
But, hmm, nothing else looks tossed.
不全是
Not exactly.
看这里
Check this out.
这是血迹
Well, that's blood.
从哪里来的
From what?
我想我们找到死者拳上伤口的来源了
I think we found the source of our victim's battered knuckles.
你是第一个到达现场的警官
You were the first officer on the scene?
没错
That's correct.
-那是几点 -呃
- What time was that? - Uh,
我不太确定
I'm not certain.
我那时刚下班 8点多一点吧...
I-I got off shift, um, a little after 8:00. Uh...
下班
Off shift?
我检查了他的脉搏
I checked his vitals...
我知道 他已经去了
but I knew... he was gone.
你认识死者
You knew the victim?
他是我丈夫
He's my husband.
昨晚七点左右 我离开家去工作
I left for work last night around 7:00,
Eric那时候很好
and Eric wa-was fine.
一切都很正常
Everything was normal.
差不多午夜时 他给我打过电话
He called my cell at around midnight...
但我直到早上才收到信息
...but I didn't get the message till this morning.
如果你想起其它事情 请联系我
Well, if you think of anything, you have my card.
稍等一下 McGee
Excuse me a minute. McGee.
我是Gibbs
It's Gibbs.
是的 我在路上
Yeah, I'm on my way.
-Kutzler的丈夫 -嗯
- Kutzler's husband... - Right.
Jethro
Jethro.
Hollis
Hollis.
Leon
Leon.
现在点完名了 咱可以说工作了么
Now that roll call is over, shall we move on to business?
国防部把Hollis派来
Hollis was sent by the DoD
协助你的调查
to assist with your investigation, Gibbs.
真是寒冷的严冬哈
Hell of a winter, huh?
国防部为什么对这案子感兴趣
What's, uh, DoD's interest in the case?
Kutzler上尉
Lieutenant Kutzler.
我们已经注意他好久了
He'd been on our radar for some time,
在过去的两周里 我一直在调查他
and I'd been investigating him for the last two weeks.
为什么调查他
Investigating him for what?
我们在对他进行审核
He was being vetted.
Kutzler上尉
Lieutenant Kutzler is in consideration
是荣誉勋章的候选者
for the Medal of Honor.
Gibbs和Hollis Mann
Gibbs and Hollis Mann,
都在主任的办公室里
both in the director's office.
你知道这意味着什么吗
You know what this means?
她会在这个案件上协助我们
That she's helping with our case?
目光放得长远点 Bishop
Think bigger picture, Bishop.
你知道Gibbs最近都烦躁不安
You know how on edge Gibbs has been lately.
是啊 从Diane死后 他一直心事重重
Well, yeah, since Diane's death, he's had a lot on his mind.
没错
Exactly.
而且他不会和我们谈论他的情感问题
And he's not gonna talk to us about his feelings and emotions.
但是Hollis Mann 他们说着同样的沉默语言
But Hollis Mann-- she speaks his monosyllabic language.
她是我们的"Gibbs语者"
She's our Gibbs whisperer.
你怎么...
Ah. How did you...?
有什么进展
Update.
呃...
Uh...
快点儿 快点儿
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
-开始汇报 -那个...
- Let's go. - Just...
死者是Eric Kutzler
Our victim is Eric Kutzler, a lieutenant
一名海军建设兵团的上尉
in the Navy Construction Battalion.
我和他在国务院的上级谈过
I spoke to his supervisor at the State Department.
Kutzler刚到任不久
Kutzler was new to the command,
五个月前才开始工作
reported there five months ago.
在那之前 他在Walter Reed陆军医院
Prior to that, he spent 18 months at Walter Reed,
休养了18个月 治疗在阿富汗受的伤
recovering from injuries sustained in Afghanistan.
按那个东西
Click the thing.
Kutzler的海蜂小队
Kutzler's Seabees unit was on a
在Punjab执行一项人道主义任务
humanitarian mission in the Punjab Province when
位于巴基斯坦 也被称为五河流域
-他们遭到伏击 -在他们被敌人压制
- they were ambushed. - And while they were pinned down
等待空中支援时
waiting for air support,
一颗手榴弹被投进他们的队伍里
an enemy grenade penetrated their ranks.
Kutzler直接扑到手榴弹上
Kutzler threw himself over it,
救了他们小队中的两个人
saving the lives of two of his men.
他扑到一颗手榴弹上 还活了下来
He jumped on a live grenade and survived?
差点儿死了
Almost didn't.
Kutzler是个斗士
Kutzler was a fighter.
一位英雄
And a hero.
也被人当做打击目标
Who someone was targeting.
2011年 Kutzler出了名
Well, Kutzler made a name for himself back in 2011.
在"不问不说"条例废除前几个月
He spoke at several rallies
他在好几个集会上演讲
in the months leading up to the repeal of Don't Ask Don't Tell.
1993年制定的政策 回避美国军队中同性恋的敏感话题
这就是为什么
Which is why
有很多人盯着他的提名
there are so many eyes on his nomination.
Kutzler将会成为第一个得到荣誉勋章的公开同性恋服役人员
Kutzler would be the first openly gay service member to receive the Medal of Honor.
你觉得这是仇恨犯罪
You think this was a hate crime?
有些人不喜欢改变
Some people don't like change.
我们的嫌疑犯调查得怎么样了
So, where are we on suspects?
我们
We?
你来这里 不是为了调查Kutzler的谋杀案的
You're not here to investigate Kutzler's murder.
国防部在这个案子上有最高管辖权 Jethro
The DoD has a vested interest in this case, Jethro.
我会留在这儿
I'll be sticking around.
给Abby Sciuto小姐的血液快递
Blood delivery for Miss Abby Sciuto.
他刚走进来
He just walked in.
她在跟Breena说话
She's talking to Breena.
Breena说不要生气
Breena says don't be angry,
她刚刚去了Beltway汉堡店
but she went to Beltway Burger.
不
No!
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
好 我会告诉他的
All right, I'll tell him.
好的 再见 Breena
Okay. Bye, Breena.
什么 什么 告诉我什么
What? What? Tell me what.
Abby 还有什么 什么 什么
Abby, what else? What? What?
她没...
She didn't...
别激动
It's okay.
Breena很好
Breena's fine.
深呼吸
Breathe.
很好 现在赶快去医院
Good. Now hurry up
因为Breena要生了
and get to the hospital because Breena is in labor.
Jimmy 你听到她的话了吗
Jimmy, did you hear what she said?
她刚刚说Breena要生了
She just said Breena's having a baby.
-我觉得你把他弄坏了 -我们该怎么办
- I think you broke him. - What do we do?
婴儿专用包
Baby go bag!
我需要我的婴儿专用包
I need my baby go bag!
这不是演习
Uh, this is not a drill!
来啦 父亲来了快让路
Incoming! Father coming through!
好运啊 Jimmy 干得好 Gibbs
Good luck, Jimmy! Good job, Gibbs.
有什么线索
What do we got?
老大哥 或者说是
Uh, Big Brother, or more like
老大哥非常非常远的远房亲戚
Big Brother's distant relatives, twice removed.
她是说来自
She means, uh, surveillance footage
Kutzler邻居安保系统的监控视频
from Kutzler's next-door neighbor's security system.
后院相机直接拍到了
His backyard camera had a direct line of sight
Kutzler被射杀的地方
to where Kutzler was shot.
录像带上拍到凶手了么
Do we have the killer on tape?
录像带上
On tape?
不 不是录像带
Well, no, not tape
上世纪90年代起就没有录像带了 但我们有视频
since, like, the 1990s, but we have footage.
就能看到这么多
That's all you see.
凶手没有正对摄像头
The killer never faced the camera.
还有什么
What else?
Vince Armstrong说 他回到家
Vince Armstrong stated that he arrived home,
发现Kutzler的尸体后
found Kutzler's body,
立刻打了911报警
then he immediately called 911.
这段视频显示 早上8:26 他发现尸体
We, this footage shows that at 8:26 a.m., he finds the body,
重新进入房子
goes back into the house,
但是没有打给警察
and does not call the police.
911通话记录显示 他在早上8:48打进来
911 logs his call at 8:48 a.m.
也就是20分钟之后
That's 20 minutes later.
Armstrong对我们说谎了 老大
Armstrong lied to us, boss.
-他在哪儿 -他和CACO工作人员在一起
- Where is he? - He's with a CACO officer.
Casualty Assistance Calls Office 伤亡救援呼救中心
我回答了你们的全部问题
I've answered all your questions.
你们不是应该在外头排查社区么
Why aren't you out canvassing the neighborhood?
嗯 我们想不通的是 Vince
Well, here's what's sticking for us, Vince.
你发现丈夫身亡 然后你决定
You find your husband dead and then you decide
先休息20分钟再报警
to take a 20-minute breather before calling 911
这看起来可不太妙
that doesn't look good for you.
我当时处于震惊之中
I was in shock.
你和Kutzler之间有矛盾么
You and Kutzler having issues?
你俩发生过激烈争吵么
Any heated arguments between you two?
当然有 我们结婚了
Of course-- we're married.
有道理
Fair enough.
你眼睛下那道伤痕呢
What about that cut under your eye?
让一个酒驾司机靠边停车时被打的
Got it pulling over a drunk driver.
你工作时没人揍你么
No one's ever taken a swing at you on the job?
我非常难相信这一点
I find that very hard to believe.
你的确有一张不讨人喜欢的脸
You do have a face people naturally dislike.
-什么 -不相信我的话
- What? - Check my dashcam
查查我的车载摄像机
if you don't believe me.
我们会去查的 不过首先
Yeah, we're gonna get to that. But first, um,
不如你跟我们讲讲
why don't you tell us about your discharge
2007年从海军陆战队退役的事吧
from the Marine Corps in 2007?
退役的原因是啥来着 McGee
What was the reason for the discharge, McGee?
行为不当
Conduct unbecoming.
就是这个
That was it.
那和这事有什么联系
What does that have to do with anything?
-那是很多年前了 -嗯
- That was years ago. - Well,
文件说你脾气火爆
It says you exhibited a violent temper
并威胁你的上级军官
and made threats against your superior officer.
那是撒谎 全都是
That's a lie. All of it.
没脾气 记下了
No temper. Got it.
听着 我处理过谋杀案 我知道最初48小时
Look, I've worked homicides. I know how critical
对破案来说有多重要
the first 48 hours are in solving this case.
你们在浪费宝贵的时间 我没有杀害我的丈夫
You're wasting precious time. I didn't kill my husband.
我们出去走走
Let's take a walk.
我全力赞成午间有氧运动 老大 但我刚吃完饭
Oh. I'm all for some midday cardio, boss, but I just ate
而且我们正在...
and we're in the middle of...
不是说你
Not you.
你
You.
马上 陆战队员
Now, Marine.
我知道这个审问策略 Gibbs探员
I know this interrogation tactic, Agent Gibbs.
改变审讯地点...
Change the location...
让对方措手不及
try to catch the subject off-guard.
-有用么 -没有
- How's it working? - It's not.
-我也这么觉得 -我们这是去哪儿
- Didn't think so. - So where are we going?
你的服役记录里有些细节消失不见
Details were missing from your service record.
所以我打了几个电话 你是一个优秀的陆战队员
So I made a few calls. You were one squared away Marine.
高分数 漂亮的评估报告
Top marks, stellar FITREPs,
即Fitness Report
各种荣誉表彰
commendations.
直到2007
Until 2007.
你的指挥官发现你是同性恋
When your command found out you were gay.
我从没有恐吓过我的指挥官
I never threatened my C.O.
他们捏造了这些指控
They trumped up those charges.
说如果我保持沉默 他们会让我
Said if I went quietly, they would give me
正常退役 而非"不荣誉退役"
a general discharge instead of a dishonorable one.
我得考虑我的未来
I had to think of my future.
为什么成为一个警察
Why become a cop?
我只想帮助别人
All I ever wanted to do was to help people.
保护 服务
Protect. Serve.
但如果连最爱的人都保护不了 还有什么意义
But what's the point if you can't even protect the ones you care about?
我爱Eric
I loved Eric.
我永远不会伤害他
I would never hurt him.
我觉得你在隐瞒什么
See, I think you're hiding something.
我猜是为了保护你的伴侣
I'm guessing it's to protect your partner.
Eric理应被当成一位英雄来纪念
Eric deserves to be remembered for what he was, a hero.
什么也改变不了这个事实
Nothing should change that.
我的工作是抓住凶手
My job is to find who killed him,
而不是政治迫害 你得相信我
not start a witch hunt, and you need to trust me.
早上我回到家时 厨房里有个袋子
When I came home this morning, there was a bag in the kitchen.
我之前没见过那个袋子
I hadn't seen it before.
里面装了不少药瓶和注射器
There was vials and syringes.
我不知道Eric为什么会有那些玩意儿 但肯定不是他的
I don't know why Eric had them, but they're not his.
-你怎么知道 -他是有不少恶习
- How can you be sure of that? - He had his
但绝不会沾染毒品 他瞒不了我
demons, but drugs wasn't one of them. I would know.
你把袋子藏到哪儿了
Where'd you hide them?
在车库里
In the garage.
我不该动犯罪现场
I shouldn't have touched the crime scene,
但我知道这事会影响Eric的形象
but I knew it would make Eric look bad and I didn't
我不想耽误他的荣誉勋章提名
want it to affect his Medal of Honor nomination.
我丈夫
My husband
是个好人 Gibbs探员
was a good man, Agent Gibbs.
我救不回他的性命
I couldn't save his life.
但是请你
But please...
拜托你
please...
帮我保护他的名誉
help me protect his memory.
有什么进展 姑娘们
What's the latest, Team Babbs?
刚得到Jimmy的消息
Uh, just got an update from Jimmy.
说Breena仍在分娩中 他听上去有点儿慌
Breena is still in labor. He sounded a little freaked.
Jimmy就要成为父亲了
Jimmy's gonna be a father.
就好像 前一天
It's like, one day
你还只是你自己
you're just... you're you,
然后第二天 你就要
and then the next day you're responsible for this
为一个鲜活的灵魂负起责任
living, breathing soul.
我不想打断你 Abbs 但是飓风Gibbs
I hate to interrupt, Abbs, but Hurricane Gibbs
马上就要登陆了 你有什么发现
is about to make landfall. What do you got?
Kutzler的药检
Kutzler's tox screen--
清清白白 他没吸毒
it's clean. He wasn't on drugs.
那我们从车库
What about the narcotics
-收缴来的这些麻醉剂呢 -每个药瓶
- we confiscated from his garage? - Each vial
都装有符合制药标准的吗啡和芬太尼
contains pharmaceutical-grade morphine and fentanyl.
前者是麻醉剂 后者是止痛剂
两者混合 就是一只
Mixed together, they make one
极其强效的静脉注射剂
very potent intravenous cocktail.
也就是我要说的下一点
Which brings me to my next point.
这批药是自制的 我是说
This batch is homemade. I mean, this distinct
看这独特的药瓶颜色和标签
color and this labeling--
-这是某人的招牌 -唔
- this is somebody's brand. - Hmm.
某人肯定是看太多《绝命毒师》了
Somebody who's seen a little too much Breaking Bad.
真怀念那部剧
Miss that show.
只要一小瓶这东西 在道上
Just one vial of this stuff fetches a steep
-可以卖到很高的价钱 -所以如果Kutzler
- take on the street. So if Kutzler wasn't
没有吸毒 或许他是在贩毒
taking drugs, maybe he was selling them?
战斗英雄转行毒贩 真是个蛮大的角色转换
War hero to drug peddler-- that's a big shift.
如果这毒品不属于Kutzler
Well, if they weren't Kutzler's drugs,
它们一定属于某个人
they belonged to someone.
愿意为此杀人灭口的人
Someone willing to kill for them.
啊 Hollis 你见到Jethro了没
Ah, Hollis, have you seen Jethro?
我刚给他留言
I just left word for him.
我暗自疑心 他在努力回避我 医生
I have the sneaking suspicion he's trying to avoid me, Doctor.
你跟上尉很熟么
Did you know the lieutenant well?
不 我们上周才见面
No, we met once, last week.
为了荣誉勋章提名
I was fact-checking his account
我要审核他被伏击的整个事实经过
of the ambush for the nomination.
我看得出来 他还没有摆脱梦魇
I could see he was still haunted by it.
是啊 身体上的伤口可以愈合
Yeah, well, the body can recover physically.
而治疗心灵创伤可就复杂多了
Healing the mind, however, is a little more complex.
我听说了Diane的事
Listen, I heard about Diane.
Jethro还好么
How's Jethro been doing?
我联系过他 但他没有
I reached out, but he hasn't returned
-回我的电话 -嗯
- any of my calls. - Well,
Jethro更情愿投身于工作
Jethro does prefer to throw himself into his work.
我努力想陪伴在他身边 可他不接受
Well, I'm trying to be there for him. He's not letting me.
与Jethro为友
A friendship with Jethro
确实要面对不少挑战
does have its share of challenges.
然而 我怀疑
However, I suspect
他一直和我们保持距离
that there may be another reason
或许还有另一个原因
why he's been keeping us all at a distance.
-Ducky 你找我 -呃
- Ducky, you called me. - Uh,
是的 我在Kutzler上尉的药检中
yes, I found something unusual in
发现了些异常状况
Lieutenant Kutzler's toxicology.
Abby说一切正常
Abby said it was clean.
这就是异常状况
Well, that's the anomaly.
他的血液中
There are no traces of any
没有任何药物痕迹
medical substances in his bloodstream.
我没明白问题所在 Duck
I'm not seeing the problem here, Duck.
上尉扑向那颗手榴弹时
When the lieutenant threw himself on that grenade,
他的身体吸收了爆炸的强力冲击
his body absorbed the force of the explosion.
他的躯干受到全面影响 肋骨折断
His torso took the full impact, breaking his ribs
肺部也受到损伤
and collapsing his lungs.
防弹衣
This flak jacket
保护了他的重要器官
protected his vital organs from the shrapnel.
爆炸向上冲击
The blast blew upwards,
使他差点失去右臂
fracturing his right arm almost beyond repair.
下颌骨断裂
It severed his jawbone,
撕裂了他的右眼窝
tore through his right eye socket,
并挫伤了头盖骨
and fractured his skull. Mm.
他遭受了毁灭性的创伤
He suffered catastrophic wounds.
因此 医生给他开了各种药物
Consequently, he was prescribed with numerous medications
来辅助复原
to aid in the recovery.
但是你看 他从没去买过一次药
But look, he never filled a single prescription.
他选择生活在持续不断的疼痛中
He chose to live in constant pain.
Kutzler认为自己要对
Kutzler felt responsible
在伏击中身亡的战友负责
for the men lost in the ambush.
疼痛是对他作为幸存者的惩罚
The pain was his punishment for surviving.
还有谁认为他有责任么
Anyone else feel he was at fault?
目前和我谈过的人中 没人这么想
No one that I've spoken to so far, but
但是当我提到要和目击者谈话的时候
Kutzler was apprehensive when I mentioned
Kutzler显得非常不安
that I was gonna be talking to the witnesses.
我要知道那次伏击的所有细节
I want the details of that ambush.
伏击前发生的事
The events leading up to it,
伤亡人员 幸存者
the casualties, the survivors,
每个参与的叛乱人员 所有细节
every insurgent involved. Everything.
在七名幸存者中
Of the seven survivors, five
有五名阿富汗平民 McGee和Dorneget正在MTAC
were Afghan civilians. McGee and Dorneget are in MTAC
追查他们的下落 其余两位幸存者
tracking 'em down now. The remaining two survivors
则是Kutzler的海蜂团队成员
were sailors in Kutzler's Seabee unit.
第一位是高级军士长Lansing Donahue
First is Senior Chief Lansing Donahue,
45岁 住在新泽西州海岛市
45, lives in Sea Isle City, New Jersey.
我询问过Donahue
Well, I've already questioned Donahue.
他对于整个事件的陈述
His statement of facts on the incident
是Kutzler获得荣誉勋章提名的关键
was pivotal in Kutzler's Medal of Honor
他不是嫌疑人
consideration. He's not your guy.
另一位幸存者是海军下士
Well, the other survivor is Petty Officer
Davis Riley 28岁
Third Class Davis Riley, 28.
2012年退役
Discharged in 2012.
如今供职于建筑业
He works in construction now.
Riley下周会接受我的询问
Riley's sitting down with me next week.
不 就今天
No. Today.
我可能查到些东西
Uh, I might have something.
我放到大屏幕上
Putting it up now.
在伏击的前一周
In the week prior to the ambush,
Kutzler收到一封谴责信
Kutzler received a letter
斥责他有妨害治安行为
of reprimand for disorderly conduct.
Kutzler的服役记录里没提到此事
There's no mention of that in Kutzler's service record.
那是因为
That's because
这封谴责信后来被发信人撤销了 即他的指挥官
it was later retracted by the issuer, his commanding officer,
海军少将Xavier Meade
Rear Admiral Xavier Meade.
-Meade现在何处 -驻守在
- Where is Meade now? - Uh, stationed
诺福克的海军远征作战司令部
at the Navy Expedition Combat Command in Norfolk.
Bishop 你跟我来
Bishop, you're with me.
DiNozzo 你和Hollis一起
DiNozzo, you got Hollis.
Kutzler是一名不错的军官
Kutzler was a fine officer.
聪明 坚定
Smart, determined.
他曾被提名荣誉勋章 我一点也不惊讶
I'm not surprised he was up for the Medal of Honor.
-是现在 -你说什么
- Is. - Pardon?
他现在仍在提名中 你说"曾"
Is. You said was.
Kutzler目前还在候选人名单中
Kutzler-- he's still being considered.
当然
Of course.
他为战友们上刀山下火海
He went to hell and back for his men.
太可惜了
Damn shame.
-你俩关系好么 -上尉和我的关系
- Did the two of you get along? - The lieutenant
与军中其他上级和下属的关系
and I got along as well as any superior officer
是一样的
and subordinate can in the military.
我对Kutzler没有意见
I had no issues with Kutzler.
除了他档案中你写的那封谴责信
Except for the letter of reprimand you wrote in his file.
看来你查得十分细致嘛
I see you are extremely thorough.
对 她的确很细致
Oh, yeah. She's good like that.
你们也错得离谱
You're also way off base.
请指点一二
Enlighten us.
Kutzler的小队到达阿富汗时
When Kutzler's unit arrived in Afghanistan,
队伍中有些矛盾
there were growing pains.
有人对他公开出柜大为不满
Some men took issue with his open homosexuality.
"不问不说"已经成为历史了
Don't Ask Don't Tell had already been repealed.
Kutzler有权表明自己的性取向
Kutzler was within his rights to be out.
我赞成
I agree.
但修改法律并不会立刻转变
But changing a law doesn't suddenly
人们的观念
change people's beliefs.
发生了什么事
What happened?
他和一名水手在排队吃饭时
He and a fellow sailor exchanged words
发生了争吵 最终演变成斗殴
in the chow line, a brawl ensued.
作为一名军官 我们对Kutzler有更高的要求
Being an officer, Kutzler was held to a higher standard.
书面斥责是标准程序
Written reprimand was protocol.
那后来为什么又撤销了呢
So why'd you later pull it from his record?
我感觉不妥
It didn't sit well with me.
这样的谴责信会毁了Kutzler的前途
A reprimand like that would have ruined Kutzler's career.
我撤回了书面斥责 只给了他口头警告
I retracted it, gave him a verbal warning instead.
那跟他斗殴的水手呢
What about the sailor he fought with?
Davis Riley下士
Petty Officer Davis Riley.
他俩相处得不好
No love lost between those two.
我还挺喜欢建筑工地的味道
I kind of love the smell of construction.
木材和木屑
Lumber and sawdust.
就像Gibbs的地下室一样
It's kind of like Gibbs' basement.
说到Gibbs...
Speaking of Gibbs...
话题转得真巧妙啊 DiNozzo
Subtle, DiNozzo.
通常我们会指望Fornell把他变回
Normally we would rely on Fornell to bring Gibbs back
"瞅啥都不满意"的正常版Gibbs
to his general disgruntled self,
但最近Tobias并不在选择之列
but Tobias isn't really an option these days.
听着 我是他的朋友
Look, I'm his friend.
不是他的心理医生 我不能强迫他跟我说话
I'm not his shrink. I can't force him to talk to me.
你当然可以
Sure you can.
你很有说服力
You can be persuasive.
Davis Riley么
Davis Riley?
有什么能帮你们的
Can I help you?
海军罪案调查处
NCIS.
Hollis Mann 国防部 我们之前
Hollis Mann, DoD. We spoke on the phone
-通过电话 -噢对
- earlier. - Oh, right, yeah.
不是说下周才见面么
Uh, I thought we were meeting next week.
计划有变
Change of plans.
昨天午夜 你在哪里
Where we you last night around midnight?
我在我的公寓里 睡觉
Uh... I was at my apartment, asleep.
-有证人吗 -看着我睡觉的证人
- Any witnesses? - To me sleeping?
我是不是遗漏了什么 我以为
Am I missing something? I thought you wanted to talk to me
你是要找我聊Kutzler荣誉勋章提名的事
about Kutzler's nomination packet.
-确实如此 -对
- I did. - Yes.
她也的确会那么做 但是
And she's going to, but...
我想跟你聊聊他的谋杀案
I'd like to talk to you about his murder.
谋杀
Murder?
Kutzler上尉昨晚被枪杀了
Lieutenant Kutzler was shot and killed last night.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我...
I...
我要吐了
I'm gonna be sick.
我讨厌Kutzler
I hated everything about Kutzler.
不能理解他
I didn't understand him.
也不想理解他
Didn't want to.
我只想让他消失
I just wanted him gone.
这是认罪么
Is this a confession?
那是从前的我
Of the old me.
我已经不是那个人了 我变了
I'm not that guy anymore; I've changed.
你转变的时间真是
What a miraculous and conveniently timed
-恰到好处啊 -阿富汗的事
- change of heart. - Afghanistan was
为我敲响了警钟 这可没什么恰到好处的
a wake-up call-- there was nothing convenient about it.
前一分钟 我们还在为学校打地基
One minute... we're laying foundation for a school,
下一分钟 我们就被全副武装的叛军
the next, we're pinned down by insurgents,
压制住了
taking heavy fire.
五名战友没来得及找到掩护就倒下了
Five of our guys fall before they can even get to cover.
军士长和我被击中了 但受伤并不严重
Chief and I were hit but not critical.
我们看到手榴弹时
Kutzler was applying my tourniquet...
Kutzler正在帮我绑止血带
when we saw the grenade.
他没有犹豫
He didn't hesitate.
一秒都没迟疑 他就...
Not even for a split second. He just...
直接扑了上去
dove on top of it.
在那之后 我才真正认识了Kutzler 他是英雄
After that, I saw Kutzler for what he was-- a hero.
否则我怎么会提名他为荣誉勋章候选人
Why else would I put him up for the Medal of Honor?
Kutzler的提名是由Gundersen议员发起的
Kutzler's nomination packet was initiated by Senator Gundersen.
记录上
There's no statement
没有你的声明
of yours on file.
这 这怎么...怎么可能
How-how is that... even possible?
Donahue军士长和我将此事上报至指挥中心
Chief Donahue and I routed that up our chain of command
那是2012年的事儿了
back in 2012.
军方表彰提名不会凭空消失
Military award packets don't just... disappear.
我猜你没有什么证明材料吧
I don't suppose you have any proof?
我确实没有复印 如果你是这个意思
Well, I didn't make a copy, if that's what you mean.
问问Donahue军士长 他能为我担保
Ask Chief Donahue-- he can vouch for me.
Kutzler救了我的命
Kutzler saved my life.
我只是想回报他
I was trying to do right by him.
我...明白 长官 我相信那是有些不成熟
I... yes, sir, I believe that's a bit premature,
但是...
but it...
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我理解 但我们的探员正在
Yes, I understand, but our agents are working
夜以继日地工作...
around the clock to...
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我明白
I understand.
是国防部长
Secretary of Defense.
媒体得到风声 荣誉勋章候选人横死家中
The press got wind that a potential Medal of Honor nominee
还被发现私藏非法药品
was found dead with illegal narcotics in his possession.
怎么会
How?
这真是个好问题 Gibbs
That's the million- dollar question, Gibbs.
媒体正准备报道这个故事
News outlets are running with the story.
我们都还没明白故事是怎么回事
We don't even know what the story is yet.
媒体才不管这个
That's never stopped the press before.
而且不仅如此
And that's not all.
他们不会取消Kutzler的提名资格吧
They're not canceling Kutzler's nomination?
这事让国会山上的很多人都十分紧张
This case has got a lot of people on the Hill extremely nervous.
玷污国家的最高荣誉
Tarnishing the nation's highest honor
-是不可接受的风险 -玷污
- is not an acceptable risk. - Neither is
海军军官的声誉也是同样
tarnishing a naval officer's reputation.
我比你还讨厌这种事
I don't like it any more than you do.
国防部给我们48小时
DoD's giving us 48 hours to clear
为Kutzler正名
Kutzler's name.
在那之后 就不受我们掌控了
After that, it's out of our hands.
这下糟了 Tony 太糟太糟了
Oh, this is bad, Tony. This is really, really bad.
好吧 我们进入一级戒备状态 McGee
Okay. We're at DEFCON 1, McGee.
我们提高"Gibbs威胁等级"
Let's raise the Gibbs Threat Level.
我收缴了整栋楼里的所有报纸
I grabbed every newspaper in the building.
来 大家聚拢
All right, let's huddle up.
我们的任务是损害控制
So our mission now is damage control.
我们要做的就是
What we need to do is
团结一致 这事会过去的
stick together-- this, too, shall pass.
-嘿 进展到哪儿了 -老大来了
- Hey, where are we? - Albatross.
你们都站着不干活
You're all just standing around.
你们最好有所发现
You'd better have an update.
我们还在追踪Kutzler被杀当晚的轨迹
Yeah. Well, we're, we're still tracking Kutzler's movements
晚上七点后就没人见过他
the night of the murder. No witnesses saw him after 7:00 p.m.,
没使用信用卡
no credit card charges, and his cell phone pinged
手机一直停留在同一地点
from the same location all day.
在他家里 看起来
His home. Doesn't look like
Kutzler没有离开过 老大
Kutzler ever left, boss.
Abby在查他车里的GPS 但是...
Abby's working on his vehicle's GPS, but...
但是
But?
Hollis Mann在哪儿
Where is Hollis Mann?
我 我觉得她回国防部了
I... I think she went back to the DoD.
你觉得
You think?
你"觉得"是什么意思
What do you... what do you mean... you think?
呃
Uh...
我们忙了一整晚
We've been at this all night.
我们都有点累了 不如大家休息一下
Uh, we're all a little tired-- why don't we take a break,
-透透气去吧 -不 不准休息
- get some air? - No, there is no break.
案子结束前 谁也不许休息
There's no breaks until this case breaks.
"办案时切忌掺杂个人感情"
Never get personally involved in a case--
你违反了第十条规则 老大
you're breaking rule number ten, boss.
你特么真说对了DiNozzo 你有意见么
You're damn right I am, DiNozzo. Do you have a problem with that?
老大
Boss...
呃 老大
Uh, boss?
这就是你说的
Is this what you meant
让我相信你么 Gibbs探员
when you said trust you, Agent Gibbs?
-我们与此事无关 -他们在
- Our office had nothing to do with that. They're dragging Eric's name
玷污Eric的声誉 这正是我所担忧的
through the mud-- it is exactly what I was afraid would happen.
我们还是去会议室说吧
Why don't we take this to the conference room?
不不不
No, no, no.
没什么可说的
There's nothing to talk about.
覆水难收
The damage is already done.
我还以为你会说话算话
I thought you were a man of honor.
你真是骗到我了
You got me.
嘿 不过是死个基佬水手嘛 对吧
Hey, but what's one dead gay sailor, right?
噢不 可怜的Gibbs
Oh, no. Poor Gibbs.
也许我该去给他个拥抱
Maybe I should go give him a hug.
我想他更想要线索 Abby
I think he'd prefer a lead, Abby.
-那个我也能办到 -你从Kutzler的
- I can help with that, too. - Did you get anything
GPS系统里发现什么了吗
from Kutzler's GPS system?
没错
I did.
Kutzler被杀当晚
So, Kutzler did
的确离开过住处
leave his house the night of the murder,
但他没有使用车辆导航功能
but he didn't use his vehicle's navigation function.
不过这款GPS软件
Turns out this particular software,
每小时都会接收卫星定位更新
it receives hourly satellite updates
并生成相应记录
and it generates a log.
在8点45分 更新记录显示
At 8:45, the update places
Kutzler的车辆停在住处
Kutzler's vehicle at his residence.
9点45分和10点45分
At 9:45 and 10:45,
他在马里兰州的伯温
he's at a location in Berwyn, Maryland.
然后11点45分 他又回到了住处
And at 11:45, he's back at his house.
马里兰州的哪里
What's the location in Maryland?
伯温社区
The Berwyn Community
-服务中心 -太棒了 谢谢你 Abby
- Outreach Center. - Excellent. Thank you, Abby.
打扰了
Excuse me.
天使降临
Bestow an angel!
你叫什么名字 靓眼妞
What's your name, bright eyes?
她是特别探员Bishop
She's Special Agent Bishop.
我是特别探员DiNozzo
I'm Special Agent DiNozzo.
你叫Mat
"Mat."
漏了个T吧 伙计
You're missing a "T" there, buddy.
通常写做Matt
像doormat[门垫]的那个"mat"么
Like "doormat"?
我几年前就把第二个T丢掉了
I dropped the second "T" years ago. Life's not about
生活不是用来遵循男权社会常规的
conforming to society's phallocentric norms.
来点自制无谷肉桂素食饼干吧
Homemade gluten-free vegan cinnamon scone?
唔
Ooh.
不行
No.
你疯了么
Are you nuts?
永远不要接受嬉皮士的饼干或电影建议
Never take cookies or movie advice from a hipster.
前面有两个人
Two guys out front
认出了Kutzler的照片
both recognize Kutzler's photo.
说他是个常客
They said he's a regular.
我问你 门垫兄
Let me ask you, Doormat,
你和你的非处方眼镜
have you and your nonprescription glasses
见过这家伙吗
seen this guy?
呃 当然 我认识这张脸
Uh... sure. I know the face.
他参加我们晚间九点半的集会
He attends our nightly 9:30 meeting.
什么集会
Meeting for what?
匿名戒瘾互助会
Addictions Anonymous.
不过从周日晚开始 我就没见过他了
I haven't seen him since Sunday night, though.
他离开时挺生气的样子
He was pretty heated when he left.
怎么个生气法
Define "heated."
我在停车场里
Uh, I saw him out in the parking lot
看见他和组里另一个人
with some guy from his group.
他们在喊什么 我不知道
They were... yelling about something-- I don't know, I...
我尽量不管别人的事
I try to mind my own business.
另外那个人叫什么名字
This other guy have a name?
我们这儿可不会关注
Well, we're not exactly following each other's
大家的社交账号
Instagram accounts around here.
毕竟是匿名互助
It's Addictions Anonymous.
抱歉
Excuse me.
讲不通啊
Doesn't make any sense.
Kutzler又不是瘾君子
Kutzler wasn't an addict.
他为什么要来参加这种集会
Why would he attend these meetings?
而且他为什么要随身携带
And why would he be carrying around
非法麻醉品
a stash of illegal narcotics?
他用的是Badger那一招
He's pulling a Badger.
Badger是《绝命毒师》中的一个配角 在剧中曾试图把毒品卖给A.A.集会中的瘾君子
把毒品卖给康复中的瘾君子们
He's selling narcotics to recovering addicts.
就像瓮中捉鳖
It's like shooting fish in a barrel.
只不过这次鳖反咬了一口
Except this time the fish shot back.
也许就是和Kutzler争吵的那位
Maybe the one Kutzler was arguing with.
如果神秘男回来的话 可以让Mat通知我们
We could ask Mat to call us if our mystery man comes back.
你想去告诉Gibbs 我们没有任何发现
You want to be the one to tell Gibbs we got nothing?
好吧 说得对
All right. Good point.
你知道这意味着什么吗
Well, you know what this means.
监视
Stakeout.
这是杯不附带任何条件的咖啡 Jethro
It's a no-strings-attached cup of coffee, Jethro.
我在餐厅买的
I got it at the diner,
所以拿着吧
so take it.
好点儿么
Is that better?
没有
No.
这个也许有用
Well, this might help.
Davis Riley说的是实话
Davis Riley was telling the truth.
2012年 Kutzler确实被提名获得荣誉勋章
Kutzler was submitted for the Medal of Honor back in 2012.
而且表彰申请并非不小心丢失
And his packet didn't just slip through the cracks.
是有人给藏起来了
Someone buried it.
所以我调查了一下
So I did some digging...
找到了一个熟悉的名字
and I found a familiar name.
你不会真的在指控我
You're not seriously accusing me of having something to do
跟Kutzler上尉之死有关吧
with Lieutenant Kutzler's death?
不不
No, no.
我们核实过你的不在场证明 非常可靠
We checked your alibi, and it's rock solid.
很高兴我们说清楚了 我可以走了么
Well, I'm glad we cleared that up. Am I free to go now?
不行
No.
你还不能走 坐下
You're not free to go. Sit down.
注意你的语气 Gibbs探员
I'd watch your tone, Agent Gibbs.
我不认为海军部长会允许NCIS
I don't think SECNAV would appreciate
像对待罪犯一样对待一位将军
NCIS treating an admiral like a criminal.
噢 我们已经和海军部长谈过了
Oh, we already talked to SECNAV.
她怎么说的来着
How did she phrase it?
"拿下那混蛋"
Uh, "nail the son of a bitch."
为了什么
For what?
毙了Kutzler上尉的
Killing Lieutenant Kutzler's
第一次荣誉勋章提名
first Medal of Honor nomination.
我完全不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
2012年 那个表彰申请
The packet was routed through your chain of command
经过你的管理层 少将
in 2012, Admiral.
那肯定是在到我手里之前
Then it must have got lost in the shuffle
就在混乱中丢失了
before it reached my desk.
因为我根本没收到
Because it never did.
不过我向你们保证
And I assure you,
我一定会追查此事
I will look into it.
噢不用了 我们已经查过了
Oh, no, we already did.
我们给驻扎在阿富汗的
Yeah, we put in a call
美国驻军办事处打了个电话
to the U.S. forces in Afghanistan,
跟当初派至你办公室的文书官员谈了一下
spoke to the yeoman who was assigned to your desk,
他把你收到的所有文件都记录在案
who cataloged all your incoming routing sheets.
没错 这儿呢 "标题
And yes, here it is. "Subject:
Eric James Kutzler上尉的
"Medal of Honor awards packet
荣誉勋章提名申请
"for one Lieutenant Eric James Kutzler.
送至Xavier Meade少将办公室"
Delivered to the office of Admiral Xavier Meade."
2012年11月1日
November 1, 2012.
要让这文件消失轻而易举 没人在追踪它
Easy enough to make that disappear-- no one was tracking it.
没错 但后来Gundersen议员的提名就来了
Oh, yeah, but then Senator Gundersen comes along with her nomination.
你这次没法掩盖掉了
I mean, you couldn't very well bury it again.
那么多双政客的眼睛盯着呢
Not with so many political eyes on it.
你对自己的手下背后捅刀子 就因为他是同性恋
You sandbagged your own officer because he was gay.
Kutzler不是我手下
Kutzler's not the only homosexual
唯一的同性恋
I've had in my command.
士兵的私生活是他们自己的事
My sailors' personal lives are their own business.
我只在乎
All I care about
他们努力工作
is that they do their jobs.
是啊 而你确保他们不会成功
Yeah, a job you made sure they don't succeed at.
从2011年开始 你给手下
Since 2011, you've given subpar FITREP scores
每一个出柜的士兵的评估报告
to every openly gay sailor
都打了超低的分数
who's served under you.
你感觉到墙在逼近了么
Do you feel the walls closing in yet?
你违背了誓言
You lied under oath.
你篡改
You tampered
政府正式文件
with official government documents.
你妨碍犯罪调查
You interfered with a criminal investigation.
我什么也不说了 我要律师
I'm not saying another word. I want a lawyer.
好吧
Yep.
领袖会照顾他的兄弟
A leader looks after his men.
为他们抗争
Fights for 'em.
Kutzler上尉就是那样的人
That's who Lieutenant Kutzler was.
你侮辱了这身军装
You're a disgrace to that uniform.
我期待在你的军事法庭上作证
And I look forward to testifying at your court-martial.
那是黄夹克的第五支烟了
That's yellow jacket's fifth cigarette.
我再也受不了了
I can't take it much more.
你该看看McGee收集的烟斗
You should see McGee's pipe collection.
我用它们来进行创意
I only use those for creative purposes.
那是...Davis Riley么
Is that... Davis Riley?
当然 我猜Riley忘了说
Sure is. Guess Riley forgot to mention
他和Kutzler参加同一个匿名戒瘾互助集会
him and Kutzler attended the same Addicts Anonymous meetings.
有人的秘密比睡衣晚会还多
Guy's got more secrets than a slumber party.
好了 McGee 该介入了
All right, McGee, it's time for an intervention.
继续拍照 菜鸟
Keep clicking, probie.
别把曲奇饼干都吃光了
Don't eat all the cookies.
嘿 Riley 还记得我么
Hey, Riley. Remember me?
你的背包
Your backpack.
-能让我看看么 -我想答案是肯定的
- Mind if I take a look inside? - I think that was a yes.
谁知道呢 看来你要在
What do you know? Looks like you're gonna be
NCIS大楼里度过今宵了 走吧
spending the night at Chateau NCIS. Let's go.
唔 我感觉很不舒服
Oh, I don't feel so good.
又来了 McGee 退后
Here we go again. McGee, back up.
Tony 我觉得他没有呼吸了
Tony, I don't think he's breathing.
Bishop 打911
Bishop, call 911!
Riley的情况稳定了
Riley's in stable condition,
McGee正在医院待命
and McGee's standing by at the hospital.
嗯 我都知道了
Yeah. Already knew that.
听说你又回来造船了
Heard you were back building boats.
打算给这艘起什么名字
What are you gonna name this one?
我不会走的 Jethro
I'm not leaving, Jethro.
除非你跟我聊聊
Not until you talk to me.
聊什么
Talk about what?
你自己 你最不喜欢的话题
You. Your least favorite topic.
-不 我很好 -别跟我说你很好
- No, I'm-I'm doing fine. - Don't tell me you're fine.
我知道你不好
I know you're not.
Hollis
Hollis,
太晚了 回家吧
it's late. Go home.
Diane之死都是你的错
It's your fault Diane's dead.
你就是这么想的
That's what you're thinking.
我没错
I'm not wrong.
不是你开的枪
You didn't pull the trigger.
我把她暴露在危险下
I put her in the crosshairs.
他那是就想针对我
He wanted to make it personal!
现在仍然是
Still does.
我正在想办法
I'm figuring it out.
但你在我身边 会让你也变成他的目标
But you being around me makes you a target.
所以你才赶我走
So that's why you're shutting me out?
-为了保护我 -我不需要你卷入这事
- To protect me? - I don't need you mixed up in this.
我不需要你和我卷在一起
I don't need you mixed up in me!
这事儿你说了不算
It's not your call.
我愿意冒这个风险
I'll take my chances.
我可以照顾自己
I can handle myself.
嗯
Hmm?
收到
Copy that.
不 我不会让你
No, I'm not
这么容易解脱的
letting you off that easy.
那次伏击之后
After the ambush,
大家一直说 我活下来有多幸运
people kept telling me how lucky I was to be alive.
可事实是 死亡轻松多了
The truth is, death would have been so much easier.
反而
Instead,
我每天都在重温
I relive that awful day
那可怕的一天
every single day.
我看着我的朋友 死了一次又一次
I see my friends die again and again.
而那颗该死的手榴弹...
And that damn grenade...
Kutzler扑上去的时候
I just stood there, frozen,
我就站在那儿 僵住了
while Kutzler threw himself over it.
我还能听见爆炸的声音
I can still hear the sound as it went off
还有对他造成的伤害
and the damage that it did to him.
我忘不掉那个画面
I can't get that image out of my head.
所以你开始吸毒
That's why you started using?
我只是想忘记
I just wanted to forget.
Kutzler是怎么卷进来的
How was Kutzler involved?
他...看到了情况有多糟
He... saw how bad it got
就介入了
and stepped in.
他让我加入了戒毒计划
He got me in the program,
跟我一起去集会
went with me to meetings.
他再一次救了我的命
He saved my life a second time.
你什么时候复吸的
When did you relapse?
三天前
Three days ago.
我没去参加小组讨论
When I didn't show up to the group session,
Kutzler就来到我的公寓
Kutzler came to my apartment,
然后...
and, uh...
他看见我磕高了
he saw that I was high.
我只记得他很生气
All I really remember is that he was angry.
他拿走我的存货 破门而出
He took my stash and stormed out.
GPS显示 那晚他在社区中心
GPS puts him at the community center later that night.
他为什么回去
Why'd he go back?
我一定是告诉了他 毒品是谁给的
I must have told him who I got the drugs from.
Eric很可能是去找他对质
Eric probably went there to confront him.
是谁
Who's that?
前台那家伙
The guy at the front desk.
Mat Jebson
Mat Jebson.
你不是认真的吧
You're not serious.
我非常认真 我发誓 嘿 Mat
I'm totally serious. I swear. Hey, Mat.
Mat你好么 哥们
Mat, what's up, man? Hey, uh,
Bishop刚刚跟我说了个故事
Bishop was just telling me this story.
特搞笑 你绝对会
It is hilarious, and you're gonna get
-喜欢的 告诉他 -是这样的
- a kick out of it. Tell him. - So,
我和McGee探员搜查了你的公寓
Agent McGee and I were searching your apartment,
我们发现了你的临时毒品实验室
and we found your makeshift drug lab,
以及上百小瓶的吗啡和芬太尼
along with hundreds of vials of morphine and fentanyl,
就像这个
just... like this.
搞笑吧 我们是这么想的
Hilarious, right? So here's what we think happened.
Riley把你贩毒给中心瘾君子的事
Riley spills the beans about you selling drugs
说漏了嘴
to addicts at the center.
Kutzler威胁要告发你
Kutzler threatens to turn you in,
所以你跟踪他回家 并朝他开了三枪
so you follow him home and put three rounds in him.
我说对了么
Am I right?
你利用需要帮助的人来赚钱
You made money exploiting people who needed help.
找这个么
Looking for this?
已经搜查过你的车了
Already searched your trunk.
发现一把带消音器的点22口径手枪
Found a .22 with a silencer.
嘿 这和杀害Kutzler上尉的枪是不是同一把
Hey, isn't that the same weapon used to kill Lieutenant Kutzler?
是的 完全正确
Yes, it certainly is.
剧透一下 Heisenberg
Spoiler alert, Heisenberg,
《绝命毒师》中制毒男主给自己起的名字
你的结局并不好
it doesn't end well for you.
我想为那天说的话道歉
I want to apologize for what I said the other day.
我太过分了
I was out of line.
Eric的名声被澄清了 凶手也被绳之以法
Eric's name was cleared, his killer brought to justice.
这是最重要的
That's all that matters.
他的荣誉勋章提名
His, um, Medal of Honor nomination would have never
离不开你的帮助 Gibbs探员
been endorsed without your help, Agent Gibbs.
谢谢你 真心感谢
Thank you, sincerely.
什么时候出结果
When's it official?
白宫应该会在几天后发出声明
The White House should be making an announcement in a few days.
英雄终于得到他应得的
A hero finally gets his due.
要知道 Eric从没把自己当英雄看
You know, Eric never saw himself as a hero.
他常来这里 怀念他的战友
He would often come here to remember his men,
那些他没能救下的战友
the ones he couldn't save.
他说 不忘记他们的牺牲 是他的责任
Said it was his duty to never forget their sacrifice.
这是他纪念他们的方式
That's how he chose to honor them.
我也会找个方式来纪念他
I'll have to find a way to do the same for him.
继续他的遗愿
Continue his legacy.
你丈夫过世时 和他在阿富汗做的是同样的事
Your husband died doing the same thing he did in Afghanistan,
为拯救朋友性命而战
fighting to save a friend's life.
他不会落下任何一个人
He wouldn't leave a man behind.
完成这项任务
Finish the mission.
有消息了么
Did you hear anything?
背景音乐  by Randall Kent
各位
You guys.
怎么样 怎么样
What? What? What? What? What? What? What?
太好啦
Yay.
我从没想过会发生这种事
I never meant for any of this to happen.
Eric应该让我直接死在阿富汗
Eric should have just let me die in Afghanistan.
他不是这样的人
That's not who he was.
我也不是
And I'm not that way either.
你为什么要帮我 他的死都是因为我
Why would you want to help me? He's dead because of me.
-我不值得被救 -Eric认为你值得
- I'm not worth saving. - Eric thought you were.
虽然这并不容易 但是
And, hey, it's not gonna be easy, but...
你不用独自承受
you won't go through this alone.
噢 她真完美
Oh, she's perfect.
一个模子印出来的
A chip off the old block.
有新生儿的味道
Has that new baby smell.
恭喜你们
Congratulations, you guys.
这位小美人儿叫什么名字
And what is this fair beauty's name?
她算是以你命名的 医生
She's sort of named after you, Doctor.
再说一遍
I beg your pardon?
和Victoria Elizabeth Palmer打招呼吧
Say hello to Victoria Elizabeth Palmer.
妈妈...会很激动的
Mother... would be thrilled.
Ducky的母亲名叫Victoria
我也是
As I am.
Jimmy 你的手怎么了
Jimmy, what happened to your hand?
噢 可好笑了
Oh. Funny story. Uh,
你们知道epidural对5%的病人
did you know that epidurals don't work
无痛分娩所使用的脊椎硬膜外麻醉药剂
不起作用么
on five percent of patients?
我是不知道
I sure didn't.
我不得不现场发挥 转移疼痛
I had to improvise with my pain management.
你掰断了他的手指
You broke his finger?
她的确是
She sure did.
准确来说 是两根
Two, actually.
但都是值得的
But it was worth it.
已经是真正父母的语气了
Spoken like a true parent.
==GA字幕组==
翻译：小末 小白 寂静流年 清欢仰慕者 汤汤忙忙忙 师太
校对：寂静流年 清欢仰慕者 师太
总校：毯子  时间轴：笑傲绿茶
英文字幕：elderman
But what's the point if you can't even protect the ones you care about? To protect the things they care about.
好久没见到米国爆棚的爱国主义了
最后好有爱啊
祝贺Palmer夫妇！